A Guide to the Charles A. Miller Family Papers, 1708-1926
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University
Charles A. Miller Family Papers 1708-1926
Digital Library and Archives, Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University, Blacksburg, Va.
Ms83-001
1 Box; 0.5 cu. ft.
This collection consists of materials regarding Reverend Charles A. Miller and his family's history.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
The Charles A. Miller Family Papers were purchased by the Digital Library and Archives in 1983.
Biographical Information
Charles Alexander Miller was born in Christiansburg, Virginia on November 19, 1819. He was educated at Washington College and later at Union Seminary. On his return to Southwest Virginia, Miller was licensed by the Montgomery County Presbytery in 1849, and served as a home missionary in Giles County (1849-51). He was fully ordained as a Presbyterian minister in 1854 and went on to work at the Kimberlin Church (Giles County, VA) and later at the White House Church (Radford, VA) until his death on March 26, 1893.
Scope and Content
This collection contains eighteenth-century manuscript items from the Miller family in Germany and Pennsylvania as well as documents relating to Charles A. Miller's land ownership and business receipts. Also included are Miller's diary, account book, and information regarding the genealogy of his second wife, Melinda Taylor Miller.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged alphabetically by subject matter.
Contents List
- Account Books, John Miller, 1708-26 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Apprenticeship Certificate, David Miller, 1799 (Box-folder 1:2)
- Authorization to Perform Marriages, C.A. Miller, 1854 (Box-folder 1:3)
- Bank Book, Mrs. C.A. Miller, 1901-02 (Box-folder 1:4)
- Correspondence, Mrs. C.A. Miller, 1893-1903 (Box-folder 1:5)
- Diary and Account Book, C.A. Miller, 1858 (Box-folder 1:6)
- Genealogy of the Taylor Family, Mrs. C.A. Miller, 1926 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Memorandum and Account Books, C.A. Miller, 1874-80 (Box-folder 1:8)
- Memorandum and Account Books, unknown owner, 1900-13 (Box-folder 1:9)
- Memorial for C.A. Miller, 1893 (Box-folder 1:10)
- Oath of Allegiance, Ludwig Miller, 1778 (Box-folder 1:11)
- Property Deeds, C.A. Miller, 1855-79 (Box-folder 1:12)
- Receipts, C.A. Miller, 1840-49 (Box-folder 1:13)
- Receipts, C.A. Miller, 1850-59 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Receipts, C.A. Miller, 1860-69 (Box-folder 1:15)
- Receipts, C.A. Miller, 1870-79 (Box-folder 1:16)
- Receipts, C.A. Miller, 1880-89 (Box-folder 1:17)
- Receipts, C.A. Miller and Mrs. C.A. Miller, 1890-99 (Box-folder 1:18)
- Receipts, Mrs. C.A. Miller, 1900-1906 (Box-folder 1:19)
- Receipts, C.A. Miller and Mrs. C.A. Miller, n.d. (Box-folder 1:20)
- Wallets, n.d. (Box-folder 1:21)